[
    {
        "question_number": "1 (i)",
        "question_text": "Study of a firm, an industries, price of a good is done under -",
        "answer_text": "Macro-economics",
        "status": "Answered"
    },
    {
        "question_number": "1 (ii)",
        "question_text": "When marginal revenue diminishes, elasticity of demand is -",
        "answer_text": "More than of",
        "status": "Answered"
    },
    {
        "question_number": "1 (iii)",
        "question_text": "The concept of scales is",
        "answer_text": "short term",
        "status": "Answered"
    },
    {
        "question_number": "1 (iv)",
        "question_text": "Relationship between price and supply is -",
        "answer_text": "Direct",
        "status": "Answered"
    },
    {
        "question_number": "1 (v)",
        "question_text": "Administrative price is -",
        "answer_text": "Both-a A and B",
        "status": "Answered"
    },
    {
        "question_number": "1 (vi)",
        "question_text": "Market having a characteristic of product differentiation is -",
        "answer_text": "All of these",
        "status": "Answered"
    },
    {
        "question_number": "2 (i)",
        "question_text": "Transportation, communication, and banking are included in the ......... sector of economy.",
        "answer_text": "Tertiary",
        "status": "Answered"
    },
    {
        "question_number": "2 (ii)",
        "question_text": "Reserve Bank of India was nationalized in the year...",
        "answer_text": "1949.",
        "status": "Answered"
    },
    {
        "question_number": "2 (iii)",
        "question_text": "According to Professor Keynes ......... is the fundamental basis of Employment Theory.",
        "answer_text": "Aggregate demand",
        "status": "Answered"
    },
    {
        "question_number": "2 (iv)",
        "question_text": "Interest received is a ......... revenue.",
        "answer_text": "Revenue",
        "status": "Answered"
    },
    {
        "question_number": "2 (v)",
        "question_text": "Balance of ......... includes only visible items.",
        "answer_text": "Payment & Recievable",
        "status": "Answered"
    },
    {
        "question_number": "2 (vi)",
        "question_text": "Elasticity of demand is a ......... concept.",
        "answer_text": "Quantitative",
        "status": "Answered"
    },
    {
        "question_number": "2 (vii)",
        "question_text": "Slope of total revenue curve will always be .........",
        "answer_text": "Positive",
        "status": "Answered"
    },
    {
        "question_number": "3 (i)",
        "question_text": "Limitedness of resources is the fundamental cause of all economic problems.",
        "answer_text": "True",
        "status": "Answered"
    },
    {
        "question_number": "3 (ii)",
        "question_text": "Fixed cost is also known as supplementary cost.",
        "answer_text": "True",
        "status": "Answered"
    },
    {
        "question_number": "3 (iii)",
        "question_text": "Profit is the difference between total revenue and total cost.",
        "answer_text": "True",
        "status": "Answered"
    },
    {
        "question_number": "3 (iv)",
        "question_text": "Per capita income should be studied in macro economics.",
        "answer_text": "True",
        "status": "Answered"
    },
    {
        "question_number": "3 (v)",
        "question_text": "National income is considered to be the barometer of economic welfare.",
        "answer_text": "True",
        "status": "Answered"
    },
    {
        "question_number": "3 (vi)",
        "question_text": "Supply holds an important place in deciding the exchange rate.",
        "answer_text": "True",
        "status": "Answered"
    },
    {
        "question_number": "5 (i)",
        "question_text": "Write one reason for increasing return to scale.",
        "answer_text": "specialization",
        "status": "Answered"
    },
    {
        "question_number": "5 (ii)",
        "question_text": "What is the sum total of fixed cost and variable cost called?",
        "answer_text": "Total cost",
        "status": "Answered"
    },
    {
        "question_number": "5 (iii)",
        "question_text": "What type of relationship exist between national income and economic welfare?",
        "answer_text": "Positive relationship",
        "status": "Answered"
    },
    {
        "question_number": "5 (iv)",
        "question_text": "Which income has been regarded as average income of a specific year?",
        "answer_text": "Per Capita income",
        "status": "Answered"
    },
    {
        "question_number": "5 (v)",
        "question_text": "What is the fundamental basis of Keynesian Income and Employment Theory?",
        "answer_text": "aggregate demand.",
        "status": "Answered"
    },
    {
        "question_number": "5 (vi)",
        "question_text": "What is the value of marginal propensity to consume?",
        "answer_text": "Greater than 0 and less than 1",
        "status": "Answered"
    },
    {
        "question_number": "5 (vii)",
        "question_text": "What is the purpose of trade?",
        "answer_text": "Profit",
        "status": "Answered"
    },
    {
        "question_number": "6",
        "question_text": "What are the central problems of an economy?",
        "answer_text": "According to professor Leftwitch, Economics problem or concentral with the use of Scarce resources among alternative human wants and using these resources towards the end of satisfying wants fully as possible",
        "status": "Answered"
    },
    {
        "question_number": "7",
        "question_text": "What is meant by Production Cost?",
        "answer_text": "Production Cost refers to all those Payments which are spent on production and they can also include the services provided to capital and labour in exchange of their services in Production. Normal profit of the entrepreners also included in it.",
        "status": "Answered"
    },
    {
        "question_number": "8",
        "question_text": "Explain the market Equilibrium Price.",
        "answer_text": "Not Answered",
        "status": "Not Answered"
    },
    {
        "question_number": "9",
        "question_text": "Write any two consequences of price ceiling.",
        "answer_text": "If the market demand at prevailing price is greater than market Supply at that price then at that price it's said to have excess demand in market.",
        "status": "Answered"
    },
    {
        "question_number": "10",
        "question_text": "Name the number of parts into which the final objects are divided?",
        "answer_text": "Not Answered",
        "status": "Not Answered"
    },
    {
        "question_number": "11",
        "question_text": "What are the four factors of production? Write name.",
        "answer_text": "Not Answered",
        "status": "Not Answered"
    },
    {
        "question_number": "12",
        "question_text": "What is Barter System?",
        "answer_text": "Bartering is the direct exchange of one goods with another goods without the use of money For eg for the services of Carpenter or blacksmith of he is given quintal of wheat then it is bartering.",
        "status": "Answered"
    },
    {
        "question_number": "13",
        "question_text": "Write any two characteristics of propensity to consume.",
        "answer_text": "Aggregate demand means the demand for goods and services. Total demand Demand for goods and services is made for two purposes 1) Aggregate demand for consumption 2) Aggregate demand for investment",
        "status": "Answered"
    },
    {
        "question_number": "14",
        "question_text": "Write the meaning of Average Propensity to Consume.",
        "answer_text": "Not Answered",
        "status": "Not Answered"
    },
    {
        "question_number": "15",
        "question_text": "What is meant by Investment Multiplier?",
        "answer_text": "Not Answered",
        "status": "Not Answered"
    },
    {
        "question_number": "16",
        "question_text": "Explain any three elements which determine demand.",
        "answer_text": "Not Answered",
        "status": "Not Answered"
    },
    {
        "question_number": "17",
        "question_text": "Distinguish between Substitute goods and Complementary goods.",
        "answer_text": "Not Answered",
        "status": "Not Answered"
    },
    {
        "question_number": "18",
        "question_text": "Write any three characteristics of perfectly competitive market.",
        "answer_text": "Not Answered",
        "status": "Not Answered"
    },
    {
        "question_number": "19",
        "question_text": "What is meant by Demand and Supply of Money? Explain.",
        "answer_text": "Not Answered",
        "status": "Not Answered"
    },
    {
        "question_number": "20",
        "question_text": "Write any four characteristics of indifference curves.",
        "answer_text": "Not Answered",
        "status": "Not Answered"
    },
    {
        "question_number": "21",
        "question_text": "Let the production function of a firm be Q = 2L^2 K^2\nFind the maximum possible output that the firm can produce -\nIf L = 5 units and K = 2 units\nand L = 0 unit and K = 10 units.",
        "answer_text": "Not Answered",
        "status": "Not Answered"
    },
    {
        "question_number": "22",
        "question_text": "Define Balanced budget, Unbalanced budget and Interim budget.",
        "answer_text": "Not Answered",
        "status": "Not Answered"
    },
    {
        "question_number": "23",
        "question_text": "Explain any four elements which affect foreign exchange rate.",
        "answer_text": "Not Answered",
        "status": "Not Answered"
    },
    {
        "question_number": "4 (i)",
        "question_text": "Demand schedule",
        "answer_text": "The general theory of employment",
        "status": "Answered"
    },
    {
        "question_number": "4 (ii)",
        "question_text": "Market demand refers to the demand for",
        "answer_text": "Supply Creates its own demand",
        "status": "Answered"
    },
    {
        "question_number": "4 (iii)",
        "question_text": "Relationship of demand for a commodity",
        "answer_text": "Directly Correlated with each others",
        "status": "Answered"
    },
    {
        "question_number": "4 (iv)",
        "question_text": "Lord Keynes",
        "answer_text": "Matching the",
        "status": "Answered"
    },
    {
        "question_number": "4 (v)",
        "question_text": "J.B. Say",
        "answer_text": "Quantity of goods purchased at various price",
        "status": "Answered"
    },
    {
        "question_number": "4 (vi)",
        "question_text": "Income and saving are related",
        "answer_text": "Demand of one Commodity",
        "status": "Answered"
    }
]